<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>misc on My Writings - Bill Chambers</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/categories/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in misc on My Writings - Bill Chambers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://billchambers.me/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DataKindSF - Data Analysis for the Greater Good</title>
      <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/datakind-sf-first-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/datakind-sf-first-meetup/</guid>
      <description>DataKindSF just got their start and the reception was incredible. There was a huge turn out of people wanting to contribute by using high impact skills for greater good. I found out about the program through their meetup.
What I found particularly interesting about the whole thing was the vast possibilities for improving the ways that non-profits do business. At Procore, I helped guide the direction of our data quality and was a led the large scale reset of our data architecture and this kind of critical thinking could really make a difference for a lot of organizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EverDone - A Project for An Evernote Hackathon</title>
      <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/evernote-hackathon-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/evernote-hackathon-experience/</guid>
      <description>Wow, Hackathons are an experience. Firstly I was amazed by the turn out, realistically probably 40 teams all competed in a 12 hour hackathon for Evernote at the Computer Science Department at Berkeley. I found the atmosphere to be supportive and fiercely competitive at the same time. Hackathon&amp;rsquo;s are a strange creation and I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled to come up with a parallel in history. But that&amp;rsquo;s for another post.
The Application - EverDone The project we worked on was Everdone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Experience Critique - Habits in Timeful</title>
      <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/timeful-user-experience-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/timeful-user-experience-review/</guid>
      <description>Several weeks ago I sent a review of a feature in an app I use called Timeful. This is my letter to that company where I tried to get a better understanding of their motivations for the user experience of part of their application.
Timeful team,
Great application. I use it everyday, several times a day! I’m a beast at a to do list, I’m just not so good at scheduling things or getting them on a calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
