<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>My Writings - Bill Chambers</title>
        <link>http://billchambers.me/</link>
        <description>something</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 09:34:24 -0700</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="http://billchambers.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>Angel Mistakes - the product management mindset</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/angel-mistakes/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 09:34:24 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/angel-mistakes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[THe Lesson in investing One lesson that I&rsquo;ve learned in angel investing is pre-supposing what I would do in a certain situation instead of listening to the founder and what they&rsquo;re planning to do. This sounds somewhat obvious, but it&rsquo;s actually a bit more insidious than that.
As someone optimistic, it&rsquo;s easy to see the potential in a product and see how founders might try to seize that potential. That&rsquo;s not going to work.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Snorkeling &amp; Scuba Diving - An Analogy Relevant for Starting Up</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/snorkeling-scuba-diving/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 09:56:17 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/snorkeling-scuba-diving/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I heard a great perspective from a candidate that we interviewed recently for a leadership role. Putting the candidate aside, he used an analogy that really stuck with me, even though it was said in passing. This saying and perspective changed both my perspective on interviewing as well as my perspective on the role of marketing, leadership, and startups.
The Analogy: Snorkeling and Scuba Diving The analogy is simply a place on the &ldquo;surface level&rdquo; and &ldquo;going deep&rdquo; that is common in industry.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Car Rental Companies and Branding - What sharing desks teaches us about product management</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/why-do-car-rental-companies-share-desks/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/why-do-car-rental-companies-share-desks/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[You decide that you&rsquo;re going to make a trip, a business trip. You&rsquo;re going to visit some customers and you hop onto whatever search engine and reserve a car, maybe through National. You get to the destination airport, stroll off the aircraft, grab your bag and walk to the car rental counters only to realize that the Enterprise and National all share the same desk.
On a recent trip, I let my curiosity finally get the best of me.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Applying SaaS Company Metrics to Product Adoption</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/applying-saas-company-metrics-to-product-adoption/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/applying-saas-company-metrics-to-product-adoption/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Overview Recently, there&rsquo;s been a renewed focus on monitoring and understanding company (or product) growth, especially when it comes to SaaS products. Werner Vogels recently mentioned something quite similar in a blog post, &ldquo;People often ask me if developing for the cloud is any different from developing on-premises software. It really is.&rdquo; I couldn&rsquo;t agree more, it&rsquo;s awesome for understanding products, how users are using them, and what you can do to improve them.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Thoughts on Shutting Down Projects and Looking to 2019</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/thoughts-on-a-project-shutdown-spark-tutorials/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/thoughts-on-a-project-shutdown-spark-tutorials/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[After having sparktutorials.net up for several years, it&rsquo;s time to shut it down. I haven&rsquo;t written for the site in years at this point and it&rsquo;s not doing me any good now that I have The Definitive Guide published.
Interestingly, I (knowingly) haven&rsquo;t published on the site for nearly 3 years. Why did I keep it up? There isn&rsquo;t necessarily a straightforward answer. I likely kept it up because it represented something.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Thoughts on &#39;The Black Swan&#39; by Nassim Taleb</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/thoughts-on-the-black-swan-by-nassim-taleb/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/thoughts-on-the-black-swan-by-nassim-taleb/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This was my second time reading The Black Swan by Nassim Taleb although admittedly I think I was a bit young the first time to fully absorb the content. That is not to say that I didn&rsquo;t get the TL;DR of &ldquo;hey sometimes stuff happens that you can&rsquo;t predict that&rsquo;s meaningful&rdquo;, but what I missed was a lot of the nuance in the actual applcation of the principles to my life.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Spark: The Definitive Guide published by O&#39;Reilly!</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/spark-the-definitive-guide/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/spark-the-definitive-guide/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[As of February 6th, 2018, Spark: The Definitive Guide has gone to print. This was the most intensive project and process that I&rsquo;ve ever undertaken in my life. It was filled with frustrations and anticipations, excitements and fears. I must extend thanks to those that encouraged me to lead the writing of the book, namely Ion Stoica, Patrick Wendell, Ali Ghodsi, and (somewhat obviously) Matei Zaharia. These folks were the ones that recommended that I take the lead on the book and I am forever grateful for them to grant me such an opportunity.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Getting Started with Apache Spark</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/getting-started-with-apache-spark/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/getting-started-with-apache-spark/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Lately I&rsquo;ve been playing around with Spark for data processing. It provides some really amazing features like MLLib and Spark SQL and there&rsquo;s no better way to learn something that to use it. I&rsquo;ve attended a couple of meet ups about Spark and its related tools including the famous ampcamp put on by the developers of spark and, although I&rsquo;m not an expert, I thought it would be good to consolidate my knowledge and teach others.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Introducing SparkTutorials.net</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/introducing-spark-tutorials/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/introducing-spark-tutorials/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I&rsquo;ve recently launched a website called SparkTutorials.net. Spark Tutorials aims to educate the general public about the utility of Spark as a tool for data science. I would encourage you to read more on the website and learn something new!]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A Simple Link Shortener in Scala</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/a-link-shortener-in-scala/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/a-link-shortener-in-scala/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Recently I took it upon myself to dive into Scala. This post describes what my reaction was after writing a link shortener service using it. For those only interested in the code, check out my github.
After learning the basics of Clojure by writing a simple link shortener, I realized that it was a great way to get to know a language. So I decided to do the same in Scala.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
