<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Anabranch.me - The Personal Portfolio and Project Page of Bill Chambers</title><link href="http://www.anabranch.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.anabranch.me/feeds/bill-chambers.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.anabranch.me/</id><updated>2014-08-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Testing Title</title><link href="http://www.anabranch.me/test-post-here.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-08-13T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Bill Chambers</name></author><id>tag:www.anabranch.me,2014-08-13:test-post-here.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This post will cover the subject of "pipeline rot" affecting sales organizations big and small. I, however feel that this most affects high-growth and growth stage companies where conversations must be replaced by dashboards and automated reports. The premise is fairly basic, I aim to define pipeline rot, who it affects and some ways of addressing the issue both culturally as well as in a CRM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is pipeline rot?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to define these words together we must define them each individually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://salesdictionary.com/index.php?term=p&amp;amp;tab=%3F"&gt;Salesdictionary.com defines a pipeline below.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a Pipeline is a term used in sales to describe the opportunities that a sales professional is working on. Each item in the pipeline represents an opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple definition that will work well for our argument.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/rot"&gt;Merriam-Webster defines rot several different ways however the most relevant are below.
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to become unsound or weak (as from use)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to go to ruin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to become morally corrupt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally we can begin to construct the meaning of pipeline rot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pipeline rot describes the opportunities that have gone to ruin (not been maintained) yet are still in the sales representative's pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This definition suits our problem well as is comparable to a similar term, &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_rot"&gt;software rot&lt;/a&gt;. It could be more generalized to something along the lines of process rot but that is another discussion. At this point we have a group of sales representatives with a working pipeline that does not reflect their true pipeline. Some of the problems this issue causes is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Difficulty in Forecasting Sales/New Revenue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most significant issue for upper management. Because the sales representative is the only individual that knows what truly reflects their individual upcoming sales. It is nearly impossible for anyone to know what they may be bringing in in the current quarter or year outside of having a conversation with the representative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common sales representative's reaction to this issue is that this either does not help them forecast or is too difficult to know when someone is going to close that it's simply not worth doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Siloed Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information generally wants to be free. If a sales rep is letting his pipeline rot and get unmanagemable she's likely dropping the ball or not making some important phone calls. However, because she is the only one aware of her shortcomings, issues cannot be addressed from a team standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This issue is particularly unhealthy because what may happen is that a sales professional may make mistakes and instead of taking ownership for those mistakes, addressing them, and moving on. He may try and hide these mistakes and furthur avoid confrontation - hurting his own sales as well as the company's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. How does it help me?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sales culture is often a cowboy v. the world mentality. The comments I get back from sales representatives and friends are often &lt;em&gt;how does that help &lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt; generate more revenue?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Sales"></category><category term="Forecasting"></category></entry></feed>