<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - My Writings - Bill Chambers</title>
        <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | My Writings - Bill Chambers</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 14:28:10 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://billchambers.me/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>So You Want to Join a Startup by David Henke</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/so-you-want-to-join-a-startup/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 14:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>David Henke, Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/so-you-want-to-join-a-startup/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The following a memo that David Henke wrote in 1998. It was a formative article for me and has helped me make serious decisions about my career and where I chose to work. I asked him if I could reproduce it, since I couldn&rsquo;t find it online, and he obliged. Here&rsquo;s what he had to say about it&hellip;
I wrote this memo in 1998 for engineers leaving Silicon Graphics to the internal newsgroup sgi.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Realestatecopywriter.io - AI Powered Real Estate Copywriting</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/realestatecopywriter/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/realestatecopywriter/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Penni AI Penni-AI is a Real Estate Copywriting Service, Powered by AI. See more on the website.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>TenantFlow AI - AI Powered Leasing Agent for Residential Property Managers</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/tenantflow-ai/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/tenantflow-ai/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[TenantFlow AI 2023-07 - Tenantflowai.com is an AI-based Leasing Agent for Residential Property Managers.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Next Step in the Journey</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/founding-precepts/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 10:46:33 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/founding-precepts/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/next-step-journey.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>this post will be subject to change and evolution. It represents the starting point for me &lsquo;starting up&rsquo;.
The Background Last week was my final week at Anyscale. I&rsquo;ve enjoyed my time at Anyscale and learned so much. I&rsquo;m grateful to the team for the opportunity to work with such a great collection of folks.
What&rsquo;s next?
The Next Step in the Journey I&rsquo;m starting up from scratch. No co-founder, no team, no funding.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Angel Mistake - assuming your operational expertise is theirs</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/angel-mistakes/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 09:34:24 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/angel-mistakes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[THe Lesson in investing One lesson that I&rsquo;ve learned in angel investing is pre-supposing what I would do in a certain situation instead of listening to the founder and what they&rsquo;re planning to do. This sounds somewhat obvious, but it&rsquo;s actually a bit more insidious than that.
As someone optimistic, it&rsquo;s easy to see the potential in a product and see how founders might try to seize that potential. That&rsquo;s not going to work.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Snorkeling &amp; Scuba Diving - An Analogy Relevant for Starting Up</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/snorkeling-scuba-diving/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 09:56:17 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/snorkeling-scuba-diving/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I heard a great perspective from a candidate that we interviewed recently for a leadership role. Putting the candidate aside, he used an analogy that really stuck with me, even though it was said in passing. This saying and perspective changed both my perspective on interviewing as well as my perspective on the role of marketing, leadership, and startups.
The Analogy: Snorkeling and Scuba Diving The analogy is simply a place on the &ldquo;surface level&rdquo; and &ldquo;going deep&rdquo; that is common in industry.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Car Rental Companies and Branding - What sharing desks teaches us about product management</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/why-do-car-rental-companies-share-desks/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/why-do-car-rental-companies-share-desks/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[You decide that you&rsquo;re going to make a trip, a business trip. You&rsquo;re going to visit some customers and you hop onto whatever search engine and reserve a car, maybe through National. You get to the destination airport, stroll off the aircraft, grab your bag and walk to the car rental counters only to realize that the Enterprise and National all share the same desk.
On a recent trip, I let my curiosity finally get the best of me.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Applying SaaS Company Metrics to Product Adoption</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/applying-saas-company-metrics-to-product-adoption/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/applying-saas-company-metrics-to-product-adoption/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Overview Recently, there&rsquo;s been a renewed focus on monitoring and understanding company (or product) growth, especially when it comes to SaaS products. Werner Vogels recently mentioned something quite similar in a blog post, &ldquo;People often ask me if developing for the cloud is any different from developing on-premises software. It really is.&rdquo; I couldn&rsquo;t agree more, it&rsquo;s awesome for understanding products, how users are using them, and what you can do to improve them.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Thoughts on Shutting Down Projects and Looking to 2019</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/thoughts-on-a-project-shutdown-spark-tutorials/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/thoughts-on-a-project-shutdown-spark-tutorials/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[After having sparktutorials.net up for several years, it&rsquo;s time to shut it down. I haven&rsquo;t written for the site in years at this point and it&rsquo;s not doing me any good now that I have The Definitive Guide published.
Interestingly, I (knowingly) haven&rsquo;t published on the site for nearly 3 years. Why did I keep it up? There isn&rsquo;t necessarily a straightforward answer. I likely kept it up because it represented something.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Thoughts on &#39;The Black Swan&#39; by Nassim Taleb</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/thoughts-on-the-black-swan-by-nassim-taleb/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/thoughts-on-the-black-swan-by-nassim-taleb/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This was my second time reading The Black Swan by Nassim Taleb although admittedly I think I was a bit young the first time to fully absorb the content. That is not to say that I didn&rsquo;t get the TL;DR of &ldquo;hey sometimes stuff happens that you can&rsquo;t predict that&rsquo;s meaningful&rdquo;, but what I missed was a lot of the nuance in the actual applcation of the principles to my life.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
