<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>tutorials - Category - My Writings - Bill Chambers</title>
        <link>http://billchambers.me/categories/tutorials/</link>
        <description>tutorials - Category - My Writings - Bill Chambers</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://billchambers.me/categories/tutorials/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Getting Started with Apache Spark</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/getting-started-with-apache-spark/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/getting-started-with-apache-spark/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Lately I&rsquo;ve been playing around with Spark for data processing. It provides some really amazing features like MLLib and Spark SQL and there&rsquo;s no better way to learn something that to use it. I&rsquo;ve attended a couple of meet ups about Spark and its related tools including the famous ampcamp put on by the developers of spark and, although I&rsquo;m not an expert, I thought it would be good to consolidate my knowledge and teach others.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A Simple Link Shortener in Scala</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/a-link-shortener-in-scala/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/a-link-shortener-in-scala/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Recently I took it upon myself to dive into Scala. This post describes what my reaction was after writing a link shortener service using it. For those only interested in the code, check out my github.
After learning the basics of Clojure by writing a simple link shortener, I realized that it was a great way to get to know a language. So I decided to do the same in Scala.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A Simple Link Shortener in Clojure</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/a-link-shortener-in-clojure/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/a-link-shortener-in-clojure/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Recently I took it upon myself to dive into clojure. This post describes what my reaction was after writing a link shortener service using it. For those only interested in the code, check out my github.
I&rsquo;ve always wanted to learn a lisp. I played with Scheme, Common Lisp, but never really dug deeply into it. Now knowing python extremely well, I wanted to try and scope an application reasonably and write it in Clojure.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Visualizing Crime in San Francisco during the 2014 World Series</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/san-francisco-crime-data-visualization/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/san-francisco-crime-data-visualization/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[During the World Series, especially during the Giants win, there was a mass rioting and looting. For our data visualization class, a classmate, John Semerdjian, and I made an interactive visualization of the crime in the city during each game.
You can view in the entire visualization here on a github project site.. The write up includes descriptions of out process.
Be sure to check out the final page as it&rsquo;s a completely interactive visualization that allows you to explore and filter the data yourself.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>K-Means Clustering - Liquor &amp; Assaults in San Francisco</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/kmeans-clustering-sf-crime-data/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/kmeans-clustering-sf-crime-data/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This notebook walks through an example of KMeans clustering crime data with alcohol license locations. This clustering is performed solely based on the Lat/Long locations of stores and crimes. The tools I use are
Pandas Numpy Scikit-learn Matplotlib The most basic question being answered is:
Given Lat/Long - can we draw some association between a liquor store&rsquo;s centroid and crime/a type of crime&rsquo;s centroid? Or another way, will groups of crime overlap with groups of liquor stores.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Interactive Salesforce Graphing with Plotly</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/interactive-salesforce-graphing/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/interactive-salesforce-graphing/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This was a post that I did for Plotly covering the basics of the tool with Salesforce.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Data Challenge - Rebalancing Bike Terminals in SF</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/rebalancing-bike-terminals-in-sf/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/rebalancing-bike-terminals-in-sf/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Leada has recently set out to email out new datasets every week with a couple of interesting questions. I thought that this week&rsquo;s challenge posed some interesting questions that provide great examples of ways to use Python&rsquo;s pandas library.
Here&rsquo;s their email.
You just made your 2015 New Year&#39;s resolution to improve your data analysis skills and become data literate! Every two weeks, we will e-mail you a dataset and some problems to work on.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Basic Statistical NLP Part 2 - TF-IDF And Cosine Similarity</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/cosine-similarity-explained-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/cosine-similarity-explained-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is a two part post, you can see part 1 here. Please read that post (if you haven&rsquo;t already) before continuing or just check out the code in this gist.
from **future** import division import string import math tokenize = lambda doc: doc.lower().split(&quot; &ldquo;)
document0 = &ldquo;China has a strong economy that is growing at a rapid pace. However politically it differs greatly from the US Economy.&rdquo; document1 = &ldquo;At last, China seems serious about confronting an endemic problem: domestic violence and corruption.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Basic Statistical NLP Part 1 - Jaccard Similarity and TF-IDF</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/tf-idf-explained-in-python/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/tf-idf-explained-in-python/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is a two part post, you can see part 2 here.
In my natural language processing class we&rsquo;ve been playing around with similarity measures and I thought it would be useful to write them up here. Obviously this isn&rsquo;t an exhaustive list but I think it would be a good resource for anyone looking to learn a bit more about ways of measuring similarity between documents.
One of the first steps in many NLP operations is tokenization.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A Gentle Introduction to Static Site Generators</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/introduction-to-static-site-generators/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/introduction-to-static-site-generators/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This document will be a simple introduction to static site generators. We&rsquo;ll go over the basics of what they are, why you should use them, which one you should use and finally how to get started.
The intended audiences for this tutorial are designers or novice developers with little to no programming experience but with some HTML/CSS skill, simple command line experience. This document was originally written for a presentation I did for a portfolio class at the UC Berkeley School of Information.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
