<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>startups - Category - My Writings - Bill Chambers</title>
        <link>http://billchambers.me/categories/startups/</link>
        <description>startups - Category - My Writings - Bill Chambers</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 14:28:10 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://billchambers.me/categories/startups/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>So You Want to Join a Startup by David Henke</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/so-you-want-to-join-a-startup/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2023 14:28:10 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>David Henke, Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/so-you-want-to-join-a-startup/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The following a memo that David Henke wrote in 1998. It was a formative article for me and has helped me make serious decisions about my career and where I chose to work. I asked him if I could reproduce it, since I couldn&rsquo;t find it online, and he obliged. Here&rsquo;s what he had to say about it&hellip;
I wrote this memo in 1998 for engineers leaving Silicon Graphics to the internal newsgroup sgi.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Next Step in the Journey</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/founding-precepts/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 10:46:33 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/founding-precepts/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/next-step-journey.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>this post will be subject to change and evolution. It represents the starting point for me &lsquo;starting up&rsquo;.
The Background Last week was my final week at Anyscale. I&rsquo;ve enjoyed my time at Anyscale and learned so much. I&rsquo;m grateful to the team for the opportunity to work with such a great collection of folks.
What&rsquo;s next?
The Next Step in the Journey I&rsquo;m starting up from scratch. No co-founder, no team, no funding.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Snorkeling &amp; Scuba Diving - An Analogy Relevant for Starting Up</title>
    <link>http://billchambers.me/posts/snorkeling-scuba-diving/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 09:56:17 -0700</pubDate>
    <author>Bill Chambers</author>
    <guid>http://billchambers.me/posts/snorkeling-scuba-diving/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I heard a great perspective from a candidate that we interviewed recently for a leadership role. Putting the candidate aside, he used an analogy that really stuck with me, even though it was said in passing. This saying and perspective changed both my perspective on interviewing as well as my perspective on the role of marketing, leadership, and startups.
The Analogy: Snorkeling and Scuba Diving The analogy is simply a place on the &ldquo;surface level&rdquo; and &ldquo;going deep&rdquo; that is common in industry.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
